JOSHUA BLUE-JACK

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Software engineer with proven experience in Full Stack web development using React, Rails, Django and a product management enthusiast.

<u>Accomplishments:</u> Successfully graduated with a Magna Cum Laude in Computer Science, enrolled and completed Microverse curriculum which selects less than 1% of students that apply to their program, 5 star collaboration rating at Microverse, Successful approval of more than 3 capstone web development projects using React, Ruby and Rails.

SKILLS

Front-end: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3. **Back-end:** Python, Django, Ruby, Rails, MySQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Slack, Heroku, Render, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD,

Chrome Dev Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentor.

Operating System: Windows. |

Software Development Methodologies: Agile.

EXPERIENCE

Highlighted Personal Projects **Full Stack Web Developer**

Remote

September 2022 - May 2023

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A

challenges) and built multiple projects both independently and via pair programming.

<u>Budgetly</u> — Built a web application to help users manage their budgets for as many expenses as they

have to improve the organization of expenses and easy tracking.Built with: React, React Bootstrap, Rails.

<u>COVID-19 News</u> — Implemented metrics app design for a COVID-19 News application. Built with: React, Bootstrap, and CSS.

Todo App — Built a schedule application to track a list of activities a user has to accomplish.

• Built with: React, Bootstrap, and CSS.

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

September 2022 - Present

- Mentoring 1 junior developer per week on code organization to improve code quality and overall performance using Slack.
- Providing advice and tips to more than 20 junior developers on how to maintain motivation to achieve longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

September 2022 - May 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Curriculum

- Obtained the Final Capstone certificate.
- Completed the rigorous full stack developer remote program where I worked on multiple projects using React, Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript and collaborated with other developers around the world.

BOWEN UNIVERSITY

BSc Computer Science

September 2016 - October 2020

- Completed a 159 cumulative total credit towards a B.Sc in Computer science (GPA 3.89).
- Participated in a photgraphy entrepreneurship program. Learned about concepts in photography and photography as a business.